William Huynh

UI | UX Product Designer

Profile _____

I specialize in interface designing and prototyping. Throughout my career, my role has varied from Web Developer, Product Manager, and now UI/UX Product Designer. All of my roles have given me valuable insight and flexibility into problem-solving. I've worked on a variety of compelling user-centered projects that focus on creating design solutions in the form of digital products and services. I enjoy the process of taking concepts and making them tangible wireframes and prototypes that can be easily taken into production.

714.363.7587

williamnhuynh@gmail.com williamnhuynh.com

Skills ____

- Adobe Illustrator
- Adobe InDesign
- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe XD
- CSS3
- Figma
- Invision
- HTML5
- Javascript
- Sketch

Experience _____

UI | UX Product Designer

Jan. 2020 - Jun. 2020

Tom Ferry International, LLC

- Facilitated the product team's ideation and discovery process by researching, wireframing, sketching, prototyping, and mocking-up user experiences for digital products
- Conducted strategic design and UI decisions related to core functionality and features, as well as new ones, based on business goals and user research
- Solely responsible for user interface design decisions that continually led to an average of 30% growth of user engagement MoM
- Translated ideas and customer insights into concepts, personas, user journeys, storyboards, system maps, user flows, wireframes, prototypes, and high-fidelity mockups

Product Designer

Oct. 2018 - Jan. 2020

Altametrics

- Created UI style guides, visual strategies, page layouts, interactions, color palettes, and image assets for the development team
- Created a range of visual design deliverables for apps, websites, products, and campaigns
- Responsible for optimizing the speed, performance, and online presence of over multiple websites and micro sites
- Maintained scripts related to web applications performance on the web
- Optimized web indexing in order to achieve 100% up time and hit targeted performance capabilities

Product Manager

Feb. 2018 - Oct. 2018

Altametrics

- Designed the overall UI | UX of consumer-facing mobile and desktop applications
- Organized 3rd party creative for product marketing and content creation
- Responsible for managing and creating a strategic product road map starting with the concept, design, and product end of life
- Conducted market research and analyze trends to ensure the entire new and current products are business relevant and competitive
- Built concepts, prototypes, and final designs for new products and feature enhancements

UI Designer

Jun. 2017 - Jan. 2018

Mopro

- Managed projects throughout the entire design cycle, from ideation to implementation
- Translated research findings from observations, interviews, and usability testing into design solutions and refinements
- Directed quality control checks on implementation, launched websites, client interactions, and website revisions
- Collaborated closely with the UI/UX team to refine and build our design system, share user research, and identify design solutions
- Partnered with engineers and product owners to provide value through designing the interactions, interface, and functionality of our products

William Huynh

UI | UX Product Designer

Profile _____

I specialize in interface designing and prototyping. Throughout my career, my role has varied from Web Developer, Product Manager, and now UI/UX Product Designer. All of my roles have given me valuable insight and flexibility into problem-solving. I've worked on a variety of compelling user-centered projects that focus on creating design solutions in the form of digital products and services. I enjoy the process of taking concepts and making them tangible wireframes and prototypes that can be easily taken into production.

714.363.7587

williamnhuynh@gmail.com

williamnhuynh.com

Skills _____

- Adobe Illustrator
- Adobe InDesign
- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe XD
- CSS3
- Figma
- Invision
- HTML5
- Javascript
- Sketch

Experience (Cont.)

Web Designer

Jan. 2017 - Jun. 2017

Mopro

- Managed the web development process from design consultation through launch
- Fulfilled on-boarding and clients' requests by utilizing the best practices and latest design trends within the platform
- Responsible for designing dynamic landing and website pages for multiple accounts
- Enhanced website structure for current clients based on web and UX trends

Accomplishments _____

- 30% increased of unique users onto my client's desktop and mobile applications while surpassing last year's goal
- Successfully created various A/B testing for user engagement that decreased cancellations by 35%
- Enhanced the onboarding process for multiple applications that led to a 20% decreased in time to sign up and while also increased more users into the ecosystem
- Created a successful in-depth walkthrough for my client's applications that ultimately led to an increase in highly satisfied customers rating by 25% MoM
- 15% increase in conversions by redesigning a client's mobile app.

Education _____

Golden West College

AA Degree: Sept. 2009 - May 2013

Relevant Coursework: Color and Design 2D, Design Principles, Computer Graphics, Visual Design Fundamentals, Emotional Design Psychology, Design Communication Arts I and II